## Nicholas Hoyt

## **Front-End Developer**

Phone:	Address:	
Email:	LinkedIn:	https://www.linkedin.com/in/nhoyt

Software development professional with over 25 years of experience specializing in user interface development for web applications and browser extensions. Experience with modern JavaScript, HTML, CSS, web accessibility, DOM events, WebExtensions API, web components and custom element authoring.

## **Experience**

2005-09 - present

#### Front-End Developer, Interaction Designer

University of Illinois Urbana-Champaign

Designed and developed the SkipTo Landmarks & Headings browser extension for Chrome and Firefox, released in June 2021. The extension enables keyboard-only users to efficiently navigate the important headings and landmarks on a web page. A complete description of the SkipTo extension with installation links is available at <a href="https://skipto.github.io">https://skipto.github.io</a>.

Served as lead designer and developer for the A11yFirst Project in the creation of five accessibility-focused plugins for CKEditor. Released in 2019, the plugins proactively guide content authors as they edit, enabling them to create documents that meet WCAG accessibility requirements. More details are available on the <a href="CKEditor Addons website">CKEditor Addons website</a>.

Designed and collaboratively developed the Alnspector browser extension for Firefox, which performs detailed evaluations of web pages across twelve categories of WCAG and ARIA accessibility requirements. Alnspector is being updated to version 2.0 with significant enhancements for release in 2022. Available for installation at the Firefox Addons website.

Served as lead designer and developer of the Accessibility Bookmarklets, web accessibility visualization tools compatible with all major browsers. Full documentation and installation instructions are available at <a href="https://accessibility-bookmarklets.org/">https://accessibility-bookmarklets.org/</a>.

1999-08 - 2005-09

### Front-End Developer, Interaction Designer

Web UI, Wheaton, IL

As an independent contractor, provided software design and development services with an emphasis on interaction design and front-end development for various corporate clients, including ABN AMRO, Accenture, Allstate Insurance, DeVry University, Fidelity Investments, HOLT Value Associates and the Illinois Institute of Technology.

1997-08 - 1999-08

## Front-End Developer, Interaction Designer

Fidelity Investments, Marlborough, MA

Served as lead interaction designer in the redesign of NetBenefits, a web application providing retirement savings account access to over one million customers. Improved the user experience through contextual inquiry, task flow analysis and usability testing.

Designed and developed retirement investing tools for 401k.com, Fidelity's website for institutional investors. Tools included the Contribution Calculator, Withdrawal Calculator and Take Home Pay Calculator.

# Nicholas Hoyt

## **Education**

B.A. in Computer Science, University of Massachusetts Boston, 1991 Graduated summa cum laude

Introduction to Programming in Pascal, Harvard Extension School, 1988 Grade: A; Undergraduate credits: 4

Jazz Composition & Arranging Major, Berklee College of Music, Boston, MA Seven full-time semesters, 1981–1984, GPA of 3.85/4.0

## **Skills**

## Front-End Development

- · JavaScript (ES6 and later)
- · HTML, CSS, DOM scripting and event handling
- · Responsive design
- Web components, custom element authoring, Lit, React
- WebExtensions API

#### User Interface Design

- Experience with creating wireframes and interactive prototypes
- · User stories and essential use cases
- · Usability testing and accessibility evaluation

#### Web Accessibility

- · WCAG requirements
- ARIA Authoring Practices
- ARIA in HTML

### Web Development

- Git, Node.js, npm
- · Babel, webpack, Rollup, Gulp, Sass
- Python, Django, XML/XSLT